Guide to the Giuliano Garavini Collection AD.MC.038
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1970-1975; 122.0 Megabytes in 33 PDF documents.
  - 24th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Fourth Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, July 12 - 13, 1971 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_027)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the welcoming of Nigeria as a new member, the question of participation (i.e., governments of member states acquiring ownership of existing oil concessions), amendments to the OPEC statutes, remuneration and conditions of service within OPEC, the feasibility of establishing a bank among OPEC members, and the proposal to adopt Arabic alongside English as an official language of OPEC. The Economic Commission produced the report from its 17th meeting, which discussed the effects of inflation on oil prices, the need for parity between various currencies, and the integration of the petroleum industry into the economics of OPEC member states.
    PDF, 75 pages, 4 MB.
  - 25th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Fifth Meeting of the Conference (Extraordinary), held in Beirut, September 22, 1971 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_028)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. The main topic of the meeting was the issue of parity among various world currencies, and how the lack of same was impacting the purchasing power of OPEC member states' oil revenues. In addition, the working committee on the question of participation reported back with its recommendations.
    PDF, 27 pages, 2 MB.
  - 26th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Sixth Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Abu Dhabi, December 7, 1971 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_029)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics discussed included parity of currencies and their impact on the purchasing power of oil revenues of OPEC members, and the budget for 1972, among other matters. Also included were the texts of speeches by Abdulrahman Al-Ateeqy, of Kuwait in his role as president of the conference; Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed al Nahyan, as Crown Prince and Prime Minister of Abu Dhabi, and Nadim Pachachi, also of Abu Dhabi, in his role as Secretary General.
    PDF, 34 pages, 2 MB.
  - 27th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Seventh Meeting of the Conference (Extraordinary), held in Beirut, March 11 - 12, 1972 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_030)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics discussed focused largely on the question of participation, and much of the meeting was given to discussing the negotiations between Saudi Arabia and ARAMCO, and the latter's perceived reluctance to allow significant Saudi acquisition of their concessions. Discussions of the ways in which member countries could assist one another in such situations led to discussion of the formation of a bank for member countries to pool together funds for assisting one another as well.
    PDF, 46 pages, 3 MB.
  - 28th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Eighth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Beirut, June 9, 1972 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_031)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. The entirety of the meeting was taken up with discussion of a conflict between the government of Iraq and the IPC (Iraq Petroleum Company), in which the government sought to take ownership of lands originally granted in the concession to IPC, but not developed, in particular around Kirkuk. The resistance of IPC led the government then to fully nationalize the company, a move that members at this meeting supported.
  - 29th meeting: Minutes of the Twenty-Ninth Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, June 26 - 27, 1972 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_032)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Observers in attendance: Trinidad and Tobago. Topics included considering whether to admit Ecuador at the status of observer, and Trinidad and Tobago as a member; the 1972 budget, and continued discussion of the issues of participation (of member states acquiring portions of concessions from oil companies operating in their territory), the possible creation of an OPEC fund for member states in need, and a review of the report of the 19th meeting of the Economic Commission, which had discussed prices and recommended a 2% increase in production, and the adoption of a contingency plan on production programming. Also discussed was a proposal to make Arabic an official language of the meetings, and the need to pay greater attention to environmental concerns in the member states. In addition, a non-agenda item was discussed, namely a news report prior to the meeting that the Shah of Iran had stated, at a news conference in London, that Iran would not follow OPEC's lead in the issue of participation, but would take action on its own due to its unique circumstances.
    PDF, 56 pages, 3 MB.
  - 30th meeting: Minutes of the Thirtieth Meeting of the Conference (Extraordinary), held in Riyadh, October 26 - 27, 1972 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_033)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics discussed centered mainly on the question of participation, with the focus being on the proposed agreement between Saudi Arabia and other Gulf states (Kuwait, Qatar, Abu Dhabi) with U.S. oil companies for their participation in concessions, and how to achieve this to avoid releasing too much oil into the market, and to allow for the building up of national oil companies. The text of a message from King Faisal ibn Abd'al Aziz, of Saudi Arabia, was also read.
    PDF, 41 pages, 3 MB.
  - 31st meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-First Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Lagos, November 29 - 30, 1972 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_034)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the 1973 budget, the working group report about the proposed OPEC Fund, a preliminary report about the problem of oil pollution at sea, the appointmentn of Abderrahman Khene as the next Secretary General, and the crafting of a resolution in support of the government of Iraq following its nationalization of IPC. Also included text of opening speech by General Yakubu Gowon, head of Nigeria's military government.
    PDF, 52 pages, 3 MB.
  - 32nd meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Second (Extraordinary) Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, March 16 - 17, 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_035)
    [xxx]
    PDF, 82 pages, 5 MB.
  - 32nd meeting: Report: "The Present Energy Crisis and Its Future Implications", March 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_036)
    Physical characteristics of original
    PDF, 43 pages, 2 MB.
  - 33rd meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Third (Extraordinary) Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, May 26, 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_037)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Libya, Kuwait, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. The purpose of the meeting was to discuss the current status of negotations between OPEC and oil companies on a way to compensate for lost revenue among member states due to the devaluation of the U.S. dollar.
    PDF, 15 pages, 821 KB.
  - 34th meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Fourth Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, June 27 - 28, 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_038)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela, with Ecuador and Trinidad and Tobago attending as observers. Topics included the membership application of Ecuador and Bolivia's request to attend as an observer, reports from working groups on the topics of the energy crisis and oil pollution at sea, a report on the location of oil refineries around the world, and the administrative structure of OPEC.
    PDF, 102 pages, 6 MB.
  - 34th meeting: Report: "The Tehran Agreement Examined in Light of Recent Economic Developments and Petroleum Market Conditions," presented by the Iraqi Delegation to the XXXIV Conference., June 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_039)
    The report suggests that the tax system put in place by the Tehran Agreement was out of date, due to changes in the markets for crude and refined oil since that time, and inflation.
    PDF, 27 pages, 1 MB.
  - 35th meeting: Minutes of the 35th (Extraordinary) Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, September 15 - 16, 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_040)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Ecuador, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics included discussion of conflicts between Libya and oil companies operating in its territory, consideration of Abu Dhabi's posted prices, and the report of a working group to analyze and consider for revision the Tehran, Lagos, and Tripoli Agreements.
    PDF, 97 pages, 6 MB.
  - 36th meeting: Minutes of the 36th Meeting of the OPEC Conference, held in Vienna, November 19 - 20, 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_041)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Ecuador, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics included discussion of basic rights of membership, consideration of applications for membership from Gabon and Trinidad and Tobago, the request of Bolivia to attend as an observer, drafts of codes and regulations to address concerns of oil pollution, review of a report on the energy crisis, and the budget for 1974.
    PDF, 77 pages, 5 MB.
  - 36th meeting: Report: "Technical Preventative Regulations for Marine Pollution by Oil in the Gulf," Technical Department, OPEC Secretariat, November 1973 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_042)
    The report describes the sources of oil pollution at sea, the prevention and abatement of oil pollution caused by tankers, cleanup operations after oil pollution at sea, and a series of draft regulations related to these matters.
    PDF, 33 pages, 2 MB.
  - 37th meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Seventh (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, January 7 - 9, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_043)
    Delegations in attendance: Abu Dhabi, Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Libya, Kuwait, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics included a discussion of the basis for a long-term OPEC pricing policy, including ways to coordinate pricing among member states in order to remove disparities between them, a look at ways to establish relationshihps between oil producing and oil consuming countries, and a review of the Secretary General's trip to New Delhi. Also, Abu Dhabi transferred its membership to the United Arab Emirates, of which it had been a member since late 1971.
    PDF, 125 pages, 8 MB.
  - 38th meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Eighth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, March 16 - 17, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_044)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela, with Trinidad and Tobago as an observer. Topics discussed included the best method to set prices on oil for the second quarter of 1974, that the Economic Commission should also, in tandem with that question, take up the related issue of how to set production levels, and a committee was tasked to meet and set up conditions for establishing an OPEC fund for use by member states.
  - 39th meeting: Minutes of the Thirty-Ninth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, April 7, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_045)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela, with Trinidad and Tobago as observers. The main topic of discussion was the establishment of a special fund to aid OPEC member states (the OPEC Development Fund), which included a report and draft resolution prepared by a working committee.
    PDF, 53 pages, 3 MB.
  - 40th meeting: Minutes of the 40th Meeting of the Conference, held in Quito, June 15 - 17, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_046)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela, and as observers, Congo (Brazzaville), Trinidad and Tobago, Bolivia, Colombia, and Peru. Topics addressed included applications for membership by Trinidad and Tobago and Congo (Brazzaville), updates on the establishment of the OPEC Fund, financial reports from 1973 and the supplemental budget for 1974, a report from the Ministerial Committee on the energy crisis, and a request for a study to examine gas prices. In addition, included the texts of speeches by General Guillermo Rodrigues Lara, the military leader of Ecuador; Shridath Ramphal, the Minister of Foreign Affairs of Guyana, speaking on behalf of Non-Aligned Nations; and Antonio Tord Gomez, Minister of Energy of Peru.
    PDF, 118 pages, 8 MB.
  - 41st meeting: Minutes of the Forty-First Extraordinary Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, September 12 - 13, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_047)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the OPEC Fund, the formulation of posted prices, and the role of inflation impacting oil revenues, among other issues. Also included paraphrased text of a speech by Raul Prebisch, representative of the Secretary General of the United Nations Emergency Operation.
    PDF, 48 pages, 3 MB.
  - 42nd meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Second Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, December 12 - 13, 1974 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_048)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included requests of Bolivia to attend as observer and Congo to apply for status as associate member / observer; the selection of M.O. Feyide of Nigeria as the new Secretary General, and the budget for 1975.
    PDF, 28 pages, 1 MB.
  - 43rd meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Third Extraordinary Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, February 25 - 27, 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_049)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the report of an expert group looking at the agenda for a summit conference, pricing of oil in certain Gulf states, and the depreciation of the dollar. Tributes were also offered to Abdulrahman al Rateeqy, the former Minister of Oil for Kuwait, upon his retirement from that post and the Kuwaiti OPEC delegation.
    PDF, 21 pages, 644 KB.
  - 43rd meeting: Report: "Currency Variations and Economic Outlook in OECD Countries in 1975 and Effects of Inflation on OPEC's Per-Barrel Income.", February 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_050)
    PDF, 11 pages, 474 KB.
  - 44th meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Fourth Meeting of the Conference, held in Libreville, June 9 - 12, 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_051)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the financial report for 1974 and supplemental budget for 1975, relations between OPEC and other international organizations, the report of the Expert Group, report of the Economic Commission Board Meetings, cooperation among national oil companies, investment of surplus funds, the application from Gabon for full membership, and the application of Syria for membership. Also includes texts of speeches by the President of Gabon [xxx] Bongo, and by Ole Algard, permanent Norwegian representative to the United Nations and chair of the board of governors of the UN Special Fund.
  - 45th meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Fifth Extraordinary Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, September 24 - 27, 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_052)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the readjustment of crude oil prices, the relative value of crude oils from different members states, the propoal of establishing unit of Special Drawing Rights (SDR) as a means to define the price of oil rather than the U.S. dollar, the potential acquisition of a new headquarters building in Vienna, and the nationalization of Venezuela's oil industry.
    PDF, 23 pages, 1 MB.
  - 46th meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Sixth Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, December 20, 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_053)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the budget for 1976, the new headquarters building for OPEC, and the reports of the Economic Commission and Secretary General, which included coordination among national oil companies, the need for OPEC to mount a publc relations campaign, and a report on the relative value of crude oils from OPEC states, among other topics.
    PDF, 63 pages, 4 MB.
  - 46th meeting: Report: Determination of the Value of OPEC Area Crude Oil in Relation to Other Energy Sources. Final Report on the Economics of Alternative Sources of Energy. Prepared for OPEC by Chem Systems International, Ltd., January 1975 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_054)
    PDF, 441 pages, 14 MB.
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1976-1980; 66.1 Megabytes in 23 PDF documents.
  - 47th meeting: Minutes of the Forty-Seventh Meeting of the Conference, held in Bali, Indonesia, May 27 - 28, 1976 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_055)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the relative values of crude oils originating from the same region but destined toward various consuming regions; the role of Group 77, to which many of OPEC's member states belonged and its support of the Manila Declaration, the status of the headquarters building in Vienna, Also included was the text of the welcoming speech given by the President of Indonesia, Suharto.
    PDF, 40 pages, 3 MB.
  - 48th meeting: Minutes of the 48th Meeting of the Conference, held in Doha, Qatar, December 15 - 17, 1976 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_056)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the 1977 budget, the headquarters building in Vienna, a report of the Economic Commission on crude oil prices, a report on the stockpiling of oil reserves by consumer states (non-OPEC nations), the appointment of Ali Mohammed Jaidah of Qatar as the next Secretary General, the administrative restructuring of OPEC and the call for a greater role in public relations, among other issues. Also includes text of opening speech by Sheikh Khalifa bin Hamad al-Thani, the ruler of Qatar.
    PDF, 66 pages, 4 MB.
  - 49th meeting: Minutes of the 49th Meeting of the Conference, held in Stockholm, Sweden, July 12 - 13, 1977 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_057)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included the relative prices of crude oil, and continued attempts to devise an equitable formula to be applied among member states; the relationship of OPEC to the Council on International Economic Cooperation; production programming, and responses to stockpiling of oil among non-OPEC nations.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    PDF, 32 pages, 2 MB.
  - 50th meeting: Minutes of the 50th Meeting of the Conference, held in Caracas, Venezuela, December 20 - 21, 1977 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_058)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics addressed included continued discussion of the relative values of heavy crudes, the impact of inflation on purchasing power of oil revenues, as well as the related impact to the weakening of the U.S. dollar, the 1978 budget, and the restructuring of the OPEC Secretariat. Also included text of speeches by Carlos Andres Perez, president of Venezuela, which focused at length on OPECs role as an advocate for the interests of developing countries versus industralized ones, and ideas for furtherance of those interests.
  - 51st meeting: Minutes of the 51st Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, Switzerland, June 17 - 19, 1978 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_059)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Includes financial and auditor's reports, report of Secretary General,and Economic Commission. Topics discussed included whether or not OPEC should join the Council of Associations of Developing Countries Producers/Exporters of Raw Materials, the recent meeting of chiefs of OPEC National Oil Companies, determination of the types of statistical data member countries should be required to provide to OPEC, and the impact of inflation and fluctuations in currency values on prices of oil and revenues, and how OPEC should respond in the face of such challenges.
    PDF, 64 pages, 4 MB.
  - 51st meeting: Report: Currency Variations Effect on Crude Oil Income Based on the Appreciation / Depreciation of the US Dollar vis-a-vis Several Baskets, and Annex Calculation, June 1978 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_060)
  - 52nd meeting: Minutes of the 52nd Meeting of the Conference, held in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, December 16 - 17, 1978 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_061)